[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 32]
I didn't plan on keeping
you and Mrs. Shen here today.
No need to be so nervous.
However, I must
advise both of you.
The criminals arrested by the Imperial Investigation Department
aren't just anyone
you can overturn a case for.
You'd better think carefully about
what to listen to,
what to report,
and what's
best left unsaid.
Don't bring trouble to yourselves
and your families.
[Imperial Investigation Department]
What exactly does Lai Luozhi want?
Don't you trust Sun Tan's words?
Of course not.
It's just that the truth is so obvious
and terrifying,
truly shocking.
But as Lai Luozhi said,
we only have speculations,
no concrete evidence.
I'm afraid for now,
we can't do anything about him.
Then what about Sun Tan's
testimony?
I will, of course, report it truthfully.
Xing,
thank you.
Secretary Lu,
you came to my place,
yet didn't even bother to greet me,
and now you're leaving?
What's wrong?
You seem suddenly afraid of me again.
You...
Have you been
arresting many officials lately?
Yeah.
Isn't that why
you and that
nosy friend of yours
came here?
What exactly are- are you trying to do?
You're not planning to
harm Yan Xing, are you?
That's so unfair.
Didn't you say
I was your friend too?
Then why are you only worried
that I might hurt her,
but not concerned
that she might sabotage my plans?
I don't have a friend like you.
I'm warning you,
you mustn't harm Yan Xing.
If anything
happens to Yan Xing,
I will never forgive you!
Well, we'll have to see
what she's really up to then.
Aren't you working at the Ministry of Justice?
Why did you go to the Imperial Investigation Department,
and even presented a dossier
to Madam Xu in the palace?
You're still having people from the Imperial Security Bureau
watch me?
Do you know
that the moment
you stepped out of the Imperial Investigation Department
with Sun Tan's testimony today,
your head was
no longer on your shoulders?
But Sun Tan suspects
that Lai Luozhi wants to control
the Gannan fortress,
and even collude with foreign tribes for ill intent.
Shouldn't such important information
be reported to Her Majesty?
And
don't you want to help Sun Tan too?
Sun Tan has been
very helpful to us in Gannan Area.
Of course I want to help him.
But I don't want you to be in danger.
I know your personality.
I'm not trying to stop you from investigating,
but in the future,
you can't be so reckless.
Next time you encounter something,
don't forget that your husband
is the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau.
I'm just afraid of causing you trouble.
If I were afraid of trouble,
how would I dare to marry you?
Honey,
what do you think Her Majesty
will decide after reading
Sun Tan's testimony?
I don't know.
What I did today
truly angered Lai Luozhi.
I didn't even know
if I'm really helping Sun Tan
or harming him.
Be true to your heart;
don't worry about the future.
Since you've conspired with Yan Xing and Xu Xiangren
to accuse me,
you surely know
what kind of fate
awaits you.
However,
you also have a way to survive.
As long as you write down
a list of the bandits
Xu Xiangren associated before he became
the Constable Marshal,
I promise
you can leave the Imperial Investigation Department alive.
You might even
become the next Constable Marshal.
You want me to frame Commander Xu?
This Xu Xiangren
is really an eyesore.
Do you know how
Xu Xiangren became
the Constable Marshal?
Back then, he made three deals
with the current Grand Empress Dowager
to steal treasures from the palace.
And he actually managed
to snatch the palace treasures
amidst intense security.
Her Majesty, valuing his talent,
allowed him to
take over General Yuan's position.
You?
Against him?
To deal with a tough rock,
it depends on what you use to crack it.
You just need to provide the list.
As for the rest,
the Imperial Investigation Department will handle it.
This is simple for you.
It's not really betrayal,
is it?
Don't you want to be
the Constable Marshal who commands all the constables
in the world?
I do.
I really do.
I really want that
token
to command all the constables!
I'm waiting for your list.
What did you steal?
None of your business!
A thief also has principles.
You stole something,
and you did it in such a vicious way.
Today, I'll let you...
Don't hit Brother Tan!
You guys leave quickly!
-Don't hit Brother Tan!
-Don't hit Brother Tan.
We'll give you all our food.
Go quickly!
He stole things,
and brought them all to you?
Brother Tan is a good person.
If it weren't for him,
I would've starved to death.
Go quickly.
Don't hit him.
-Don't hit him.
-He's a good man.
Yes, he's a good man.
Don't hit him!
Don't steal anymore.
Come work for me.
Stop pretending to be good here.
Look at you,
you don't even look rich.
Maybe you're even worse than me.
It's just that my skills aren't good enough now.
Once I've honed my skills,
I'll be able to steal anything from the palace.
Alright.
Just you wait.
I'm going to
steal treasures from the palace
and show you all.
Be gentle.
These...
are all stolen from the palace by you?
I've already promised the Grand Empress Dowager.
From now on,
I am
the Constable Marshal commanding all the constables
in the world.
If you're
willing to follow me in the future,
you'll all become constables.
I don't want to be a constable.
I want to be
the Constable Marshal.
Right?
-Yes.
You have ambition.
Then you need to find a way
to defeat me first.
Get down.
One day, when I become stronger,
I will kill you.
Alright.
Then I promise you this.
When I die some day,
[Constable Marshal]
this Constable Marshal's token
♫Grudges and debts, right and wrong♫
will be yours.
Deal.
♫The past is shrouded in blood and tears♫
I promise you.
I'll follow you
♫It's been a long time since we parted♫
until the day you die.
♫Can't fully explain the true story♫
♫Fate twists and turns♫
I'm not dead yet.
This token
♫Life and death, fortune and misfortune, always intertwined♫
is still waiting for you to claim it.
♫Obsession is hard to dispel, retain the true and discard the false♫
♫Let the wind blow♫
But you're not dead yet.
♫Through thick and thin, unwavering in heart♫
How can I take what's yours?
♫I'll be with you forever♫
♫At least I have you to share both joy and sorrow♫
♫Unravel fate, fearless and unyielding♫
[Constable Marshal]
♫A dream brings me back♫
♫The scenery is bright, hand in hand, we go back together♫
[Without a great leader like Commander Xu, the world would be in chaos.]
Xing,
this is sent by the Imperial Investigation Department.
It's for you.
I thought
Lai Luozhi would cause you trouble.
Seeing that you're fine today,
I feel relieved.
[The criminal Sun Tan refused to confess and has committed suicide out of guilt.]
Xing,
what does this document say?
[The criminal Sun Tan refused to confess and has committed suicide out of guilt.]
Sun Tan committed suicide out of guilt.
He still died.
That bastard
Lai Luozhi!
Xu,
I caused Sun Tan's death.
Commander Xu knew you'd think this way,
so we rushed here as soon as
we got the news.
What Sun Tan wanted to say
has already been conveyed through your report.
He chose to end his life.
Firstly, he wanted to protect
the brothers in Gannan Area.
Secondly...
He wanted to protect me.
Brother,
may you rest in peace.
Xing,
why did you drink?
Come.
Lift your foot.
Is it because of Sun Tan?
Sun Tan was
a brave real man.
I failed to protect him.
Today, I intended to
go to the palace to plead for him,
but I was still too late.
Sun Tan died too wrongfully.
Look at this.
A letter from Pan Chi.
Pan Chi.
At a time like this,
why are you still being jealous?
It's important.
It's about the old case of the Shen family.
Look.
Pan Chi wrote granary fire
[Granary fire
Accelerant technique]
and accelerant technique.
This means that the granary fire,
which led to the Shen family's conviction,
was deliberately fueled
by accelerant technique.
But this pattern on the jade pendant...
What about it?
This is the pattern
of the pendant given by the late emperor
to the Zhou family during his wedding
with the Grand Empress Dowager.
The Zhou family?
Could Pan Chi be suggesting
that fire
was set by the Zhou family?
The one who caused the death of
the entire Shen family
was never anyone else
but Zhou Xu herself
of the Zhou family.
The accelerant technique is a secret method of the Fire Moth Sect.
How could it be related to the Zhou family?
Xing,
do you want to go back and rest?
No.
I promised to
find the truth with you.
Now we've finally found
a clue.
But how could it be the Zhou family?
Grand Commander,
here's the secret report sent from Gannan Area.
It's
the autopsy result of those
Half-faced Ghost corpses in Gannan Area.
The triangular needle marks,
upon examination,
reveal that the victims were poisoned with a slow-acting poison
called "Ten-Day Reaper."
As the name suggests,
[Yuanniang had triangular needle marks on her body.]
ten days after being poisoned,
the reaper claims
their lives.
Xing.
The deceased have triangular
needle marks on their necks.
Yuanniang...
Yuanniang had them too.
Shen Du, do you remember,
the day of the state preceptor's memorial,
when I was captured by you?
I was actually investigating
the Yuanniang case on the mountain.
The case was originally closed as a crime of passion,
but when I was
organizing the files,
I discovered that,
on Yuanniang's body,
there were also triangular needle marks.
It indicates that Yuanniang
was also likely poisoned by
the Ten-Day Reaper.
Why would the Fire Moth Sect target her
and use a slow-acting poison?
An ordinary woman in the mountain
being targeted
and poisoned with a slow-acting poison—
there's only one possibility.
She knew something
she shouldn't have
and was silenced.
Go investigate
whether she had
any special identity
or any other secrets.
Yes.
It seems the granary was
indeed empty back then.
Using the Fire Moth Sect's accelerant technique
to burn the granary
was to cover up
the fact that the granary was already empty.
I'm afraid Lai Luozhi
is involved in this matter.
As for the Zhou family...
Xing,
thank you.
It seems now
that the forces behind the Shen family's
wrongful accusation are deeply entrenched.
We can't be hasty now.
Xing,
no matter what,
I don't want anything to happen to you.
Shen Du.
What time is it?
Don't worry.
Today is a day off.
You got drunk last night.
Pan Chi's letter...
It's very useful.
The network behind
the Shen family's case
is about to reveal itself.
Thank you.
Yuanniang.
Ten-Day Reaper.
Jing Lin has already investigated.
She was not only
a farmer from the nearby mountains,
but also in charge of cleaning the Ming Hall during her lifetime.
Ming Hall?
When the state preceptor was alive,
he also lived in Ming Hall.
But since the state preceptor passed away,
all the people related to Ming Hall
have disappeared without a trace.
Could all of this
be related to the state preceptor's death?
Could it be that the state preceptor...
After the state preceptor made
his last prophecy,
he passed away shortly.
I've heard rumors
that the state preceptor's last prophecy was
"The phoenix leads nine chicks; The world is at peace."
There's an unknown
second half to it.
If that's the case,
the state preceptor's death
might also be very suspicious.
Could it be that
the state preceptor's death,
Yuanniang's death,
and the disappearance of people related to Ming Hall
are all related to that prophecy?
Madam,
someone from the palace has come to deliver an imperial edict,
saying Her Majesty
has summoned you alone to the palace.
I'll go with you.
Her Majesty
has requested that I go alone.
Alright, Uncle Zhong,
I understand.
Please ask the messenger to wait a moment.
I'll get changed and head over right away.
Yes.
Wait for me to come back.
Be mindful of your actions,
and do not act impulsively.
Also,
do not mention anything
related to Sun Tan.
Do not bring up any news about Lai Luozhi.
Never mention the Shen family.
Alright,
I got it.
When did you
become so long-winded?
Madam Xu.
This isn't the way to the study.
We're not going to the study today.
Her Majesty is waiting for you in her bedchamber.
Bedchamber?
Your Majesty.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Get up.
Emerald cakes.
This is my
favorite food.
I can't eat much now.
Eating just half a piece,
I'll be full for half a day.
I'm not like you young people.
Try some.
These emerald cakes
are extremely rare.
It's made with
rouge rice offered as tribute from the Western Regions,
which is sun-dried and ground into powder,
then mixed with lotus leaf powder.
The filling is even more complex.
Her Majesty
rarely rewards anyone with this delicacy.
Try it now,
and see how it differs from those made outside the palace.
It's actually salty.
So, whether it's these pastries
or people,
sometimes you can't see clearly
or might misjudge them
just by appearances.
You're always so clever with your words.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
it will be the beginning of winter in a couple of days.
You must not catch a cold.
You all
think I'm old.
Your Majesty,
you are a blessing to Cang State.
People all wish for your
longevity,
always blessing Cang State.
Yan Xing,
do you know why I summoned you
this time?
I do not know, Your Majesty.
There are some matters
I want to clarify.
Firstly,
I've heard that
the former prefectural governor of Yingzhou,
Mo Qianzhi, claimed before his death
that the Shen family's old case
was directed by me.
Shen Du is loyal
to Your Majesty,
and so am I.
Don't panic.
Get up and explain in detail.
Mo Qianzhi did say that,
but Shen Du
has served Your Majesty for many years;
how could he be deceived by a few words?
Moreover,
Mo Qianzhi
was also deceived by villains
to believe such statements.
In order to repay his teacher's kindness,
Mo Qianzhi has always had an obsession
to uncover the truth about the Shen family from years ago.
Therefore, he was lured
into the wrong path,
becoming an executioner for the Fire Moth Sect,
and made a big mistake.
As for the second matter,
the Fire Moth Sect has been in Yingzhou for many years
without leaking even the slightest hint.
Does this Fire Moth Sect
have any other forces elsewhere?
Well...
I'm afraid they do.
But it is not known
what form they appear
in public.
The Yingzhou case is one example.
If one Mo Qianzhi falls,
will there be
more Mo Qianzhis emerging?
Your Majesty is diligent in governance and loves the people.
People live and work in peace and contentment.
There certainly won't be more
people like Mo Qianzhi
emerging.
Back then, when I
ascended to the throne with the young emperor,
I had to bear so much slander.
How many people can
truly understand my helplessness?
Everyone
wants to live comfortably.
But since I'm in this position,
I can only
bear the responsibilities of the position.
As the Grand Empress Dowager,
I know the road ahead is dim,
but I have never given up.
Qi'er is still young,
and I, a woman, am in charge.
How many men in the world are convinced?
But I must make them convinced!
These years have been relatively stable,
not failing the late emperor's trust.
Your Majesty's demeanor
is the model
for all women in Cang State.
There's one more thing.
Regarding Sun Tan's death,
I know you
submitted the petition to the palace under pressure.
However, Sun Tan
still died under mysterious circumstances.
Do you think
that I
allowed Lai Luozhi to act recklessly?
Your Majesty
needs Lord Lai to supervise all officials,
requiring the overwhelming power.
But I know
no one is perfect and everyone makes mistakes.
If there's anything wrong in the case,
I'm willing to be the honest one
to correct mistakes.
Good.
So frank and honest.
Yan Xing, you're quite straightforward.
I like that.
Do you know
that Lai Luozhi
paid me a visit last night?
He spoke highly of your achievements.
He even asked me
to make good use of you.
I am truly honored.
I have no connection with Lord Lai,
and I don't know
why Lord Lai recommended
me.
I
don't want any rewards or promotions.
I just want to examine bodies and solve cases,
to uncover the truth
and bring justice to the deceased.
Alright, alright. Get up quickly.
How many times
have you knelt in this short while?
Get up quickly.
Come.
Come over.
Take this.
Looking at you
reminds me of my younger days.
Come to the palace more often
when you have time and keep me company.
Alright?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[Zhaotai Palace]
Have you heard of Consort Shu?
The late emperor's
Consort Shu from Nanlang?
I've heard a little about her.
This place was once
the residence granted to Consort Shu by the late emperor.
There are rumors
[Zhaotai Palace]
that Consort Shu was killed
by the Grand Empress Dowager, who was then the Empress,
over a struggle for favor.
But in fact, Consort Shu died of melancholy,
missing her homeland.
It's just another
sad story of unfulfilled desire
in this palace.
Now that you have
a pass to come and go freely in the palace,
you should understand that
the emperor's favor is as deep as the sea
but also as heavy as a mountain.
I feel overwhelmed.
Please give me some guidance.
A few days ago, I helped submit
Sun Tan's testimony for you.
Her Majesty didn't express any opinion.
Then Lai Luozhi
deliberately praised you before Her Majesty.
Today, Her Majesty
specially invited you here,
giving you a chance to speak.
You should understand that
Her Majesty has to
consider public opinion
and also ensure the loyalty of her subjects
in this male-dominated world.
I used to think that
everything in the world was either black or white,
but after experiencing so much,
I've come to understand a little more.
Her Majesty intends to show you favor.
Firstly, she genuinely values you,
and secondly,
it's also for Shen Du's sake.
You were married into the Shen family
through Minister Zhang's efforts.
[Zhaotai Palace]
Now,
Lai Luozhi also shows you great favor.
It's hard not to suspect
that you might be a spy
between both sides.
[Zhou]
I'm Yan Xing, the chief clerk of the Ministry of Justice.
Greetings, Lord Lai.
Mrs. Shen, you've been with Shen Du for so long.
I'm not sure about other things,
but your boldness has certainly grown.
I'm not sure what you mean by that.
Even the cases that the Minister of
the Court of Judicial Review avoids,
you dare to take the lead
in reviewing.
It must be because you have
the support of the Imperial Security Bureau, right?
And the constables, those bandits,
are also willing to help you.
But even if you
try everything you can,
the Sun Tan case
won't affect me at all.
You'd better see the situation clearly.
Thank you for the reminder, Lord Lai.
I don't have any great talents or strategies,
so naturally, I don't
consider things thoroughly.
Speaking of which,
your sister's truly admirable.
She excels in both civil and military affairs,
unmatched in the world.
Oh, by the way,
the other day when my husband and I
were strolling on the streets of Yingzhou,
my husband said
he seemed to have seen your sister.
What nonsense are you talking about?
Recently, it's been cold.
My sister has been resting at home.
A few days ago,
she went out to play with the families
of several officials.
How could she have gone to Yingzhou?
If you're trying to frame someone,
you need evidence, don't you?
If Shen Du can't teach you properly,
why don't you come to my place?
I'll definitely...
teach you how to do things properly.
Is that so?
Then I wish your sister
good health, Lord Lai.
I take my leave now.
Oh, right.
Prince Xian
is hosting a banquet for officials on the Winter Solstice.
I assume the Shen's Mansion
has also received an invitation.
Mrs. Shen,
I'll see you at the Prince Xian's Mansion then.
[Chengtian Gate]
Shen Du.
Someone in the palace sent me a message
that Lai Luozhi intercepted you on the way.
I rushed over immediately.
Did he do anything to you?
Your ears are red from the cold.
You usually complain that carriage's too slow.
Why did you take a carriage today?
It's cold.
Riding a horse would be colder.
I didn't know
you were so thoughtful.
How was your audience with Her Majesty today?
[Zhou]
Her Majesty's private pass.
Madam Xu reminded me of something.
The Emperor's favor is as deep as the sea,
but also as heavy as a mountain.
If I'm not mistaken,
while Her Majesty asked the Imperial Security Bureau
to monitor the Imperial Investigation Department
and Lai Luozhi,
Lai Luozhi also received a secret order
to monitor my Imperial Security Bureau.
No wonder today
Lai Luozhi
deliberately waited for me at the palace gate
and even praised me
in front of Her Majesty.
He must have guessed it too.
Oh, right.
Will Lai Luozhi try to play tricks
at the banquet
in Prince Xian's Mansion?
Don't worry.
I will protect you.
Let's go.